Tudor Popescu

tudor.m.p@outlook.com · +447465402934 · London SE8 · 2d0r.github.io

Summary

I am a **Front-End Developer** with 3 years experience building & designing web apps. Math and logic are second nature. I have a sharp eye for intuitive design. Writing and producing songs is my hobby.

Skills

React Next.

Next.js No

Node.js Typescript

ript

Qit SASS

Tailwind

JavaScript

Redux

Python

PostgreSQL)

Prisma

Figma Sketch

Photoshop

Pixelmator

Experience

Web Developer

WeJam, 2022 - present

Maintained and improved the React and node.js codebases of the WeJam immersive band experience.

Overhauled the UI design, improved user journeys, created new screens such as Leaderboard to add to the experience. Solved connectivity and server-messaging issues.

Freelance Web and UX Designer

2022 - present

Created UX project for a sports booking app, for mobile and web, in Figma. Created and updated visual assets using Figma, Sketch and Pixelmator Pro.

Designed and implemented landing sites for various clients. I used Figma, Squarespace, Wix.

Trainee Developer

WeJam, 2022

Cut my teeth automating stages of the song score processing using Python and Lillypond (a music engraving language). Learnt React.js from mid-level developer through pair-programming.

Song Production Assistant

WeJam, 2021

Prepared song scores to be processed and added to the experience. I did my first UX project for the Stats screen.

Projects

Kronos • 2023 - 2024

Built a smart organiser app in Next.js with Typescript and Tailwind CSS, postgreSQL database, and Prisma as ORM.

Learnt to separate client from server components. Learnt to manage state using Redux and callback functions. Learnt to handle local and UTC dates. Used third-party libraries for calendar and timer UI. Set up local database in Docker. Used Server Actions to fetch data and query the database.

2d0r Portfolio • 2024

Built my online portfolio as a Next.js static site, hosted on QitPages. Used Typescript, Tailwind CSS, Framer Motion for animations, TipTap for markdown notes editor.

Wolfpack • 2023

Created responsive landing page for Wolfy's Bar NFTs using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Desgined project in Figma.

Education

Front-End Engineer • Sep 2024 Professional Certification by Codecademy

React · Redux · JavaScript · HTML · CSS Async Functions · APIs · Testing with Mocha Algorithms · Data Structures

Product Design • LoveCircular • 2022

UI Design Principles · User Research · Design Systems The Double Diamond · Collaborating with Developers Figma · Wireframing · Prototyping

Computer Science College

95% Grade in the Romanian Baccalaureate

Finished top-tier college, Andrei Saguna in top 30% of class. Learnt math algorithms in C++, HTML, CSS and JavaScript.

Qualified for the national Information Technology Olympiad.